Hi there, so today we are going to talk
about Scrapy feed exports.
The reason why we build Spiders is because we want to
gather data from the sites; gathered data is then exported
to the various data formats.
Traditionally if you're building Spider from the ground up
you will have to build data experts yourself.
But Scrapy
out of the box offers to save data to CSV, JSON and XML,
which in a moment we will run, which in other words
helps out really tremendously when it comes to
speeding up coding spiders so you will spend less time
worrying if your exports are not working correctly.
So let's run a few examples.
And the way that we are going to run is by typing
scrapy crawl books
Feed exports are defined by
"-o" which stands for output.
For example we will name the output,
for example "items",
it doesn't really matter.
What matters is the extension so CSV or JSON or XML,
once again is supported out of the box.
Let's try the ".csv" which is going to yield a bunch of column names.
The column names are going to be from
the yield statement that we specified here
from the dictionary keys.
And here are pretty much results in this case.
The other data format as I was saying is JSON.
So just to run it with or to output the data
in to JSON just type in ".json".
Let's run it and let's open the file that is getting generated
in the root directory in the text editor
and let's prettify it.
And as you can see in this curly brackets
we get the one row of the data for example that will be represented
in the CSV file and the latest output or feed export
that Scrapy offers is XML, let's run that.
And if we open the .xml file, in Chrome or in your text editor,
we will see again in the results
pretty much in the XML output.
So once again this helps out tremendously when building Spiders
and saves a lot of time and you can of course
output data to TXT or write Spiders to output data to TXT
or some database like MySQL.
And that would be it for this video.
And thanks for watching.
Bye!