Hey there! So today we are going
to learn how to transform the CSV file
to the XLSX or aka Excel file.
If you don't already have
the tool called openpyxl, then
you can go to either the Terminal
or your Command Prompt, and then type in
sudo or just pip install openpyxl. Hit Enter.
Then if prompted, of course, as always,
make sure to enter your password.
Hit once again Enter and then
the tool should be downloaded.
Now we can close the Terminal, and go
to the Course Content. And, pretty much,
the code, really, that I'm going to write can
be, really, modified to, really, any other spider,
but for now we can use on the Section 3
called Building Basic Spider with Scrapy,
we can download this
3.3.quotes-spider-basic.zip file.
And since I've already done this, if I go
to the Desktop, and then extract it.
We can remove it. And then we can go to
the spider quotes, which is located here,
and then open it with the text editor.
So this is fairly straightforward.
Or let's use, not the example.py, let's use
the quotes.py. The spider, as you can see,
it's pretty straightforward. So it
goes to the quotes.toscrape.com,
and then it just scrapes the h1 tag,
and also the tags. So if we run it,
let's go to the root directory. So we
run it with the scrapy crawl quotes.
So we open the Terminal in the root directory,
and then type in scrapy crawl quotes. Hit Enter.
And, as you can see, it's already finished.
So since we are only scraped one page,
we are then if we use a feed export,
such as -o items.csv, for example,
we will just generate one row
of data, as you can see from here.
Okay. We can delete this, and now
there are a few imports that we need to use.
The first one is the os, so we import
the os. Also, we import the csv module,
also the glob, and, finally,
the already installed, openpyxl,
and we import Workbook from it, so
Workbook. And that will be it for the imports.
Then here we need to add
another method called close.
This is one of the Scrapy default
names such as, for example, parse.
Close is also one of the, again,
Scrapy default names that Scrapy uses.
And the two parameters, the first one is
self, and then the second one is reason.
Okay? So it's not the response. And
then this method is only called once
the Scrapy is completely
finished, really, with the scraping.
So the first thing that we'll do is call
in the CSV file as a variable name,
and then, pretty much, this line that I'm
going to write will get the latest CSV file.
So we type in max(glob.iglob), and then
in open and closed parentheses we will,
pretty much, find every CSV file. So the
syntax is dot csv and then asterisk (*)
for every, really, file that has the CSV
extension. And then we will define key
as os.path.getctime
Then here we will assign
wb is equal to the already referenced Workbook from
the openpyxl module, open and closed parentheses,
and type in then ws = wb.active
Then, finally, we will open the CSV
and save the... or first append rows
and then save the file as Excel or xlsx file.
So to do that, first, again, we need to open the file.
We do that with the with open, then the CSV file.
So we can copy this, paste it here,
then set the CSV file to read mode,
and then set the CSV file as an "f"
and then we can start to iterate
over it. So for row in csv.reader
Then we can reference the "f" ws.append,
obviously, the row. And then we can finally...
the last line is for saving. So we can call in
wb.save csv file. Then we are going
to replace the .csv with nothing.
And then we will add plus .xlsx.
So this will be our Excel file.
Finally, we can save this, then go
to the Terminal and then run this once again.
And then go to the root directory. And,
as you can see, right now we have the items.csv
and then also items.xlsx or Excel file.
So if we open the CSV file,
we can see the results. And then,
obviously, if we open the Excel file,
you will see the same, really, results.
But in the Excel or .xlsx extension.
So that will be it for this video,
and I'll see you in the very next one.