Hey there! So this is the fourth part of
our LinkedIn automation project,
and in this part we will finally scrape some data
points from each and every LinkedIn profile.
So we go back to our script.py file,
and we start to iterate over LinkedIn URLs.
So if we copy this and if you
remember... let's actually close this,
and just use this one. So if you
remember correctly, in the LinkedIn URLs,
it's going to be really the ten URLs
per page of the LinkedIn profiles.
So to go, what we really need to do is go
into each and every one, and then scrape
data points from them, such as name, also the
job title, school location, and also the LinkedIn URL.
Let's close this, go back to our
text editor, and to iterate, of course,
we can use for loops. So let's do that. So
for linkedin_url in linkedin_urls or, really, this link.
We go and type in driver.get()
and we can copy pretty much this.
Sorry, not cut. Copy, paste it here, and then
we can type in, for example here, to sleep,
let's say, five seconds between
loading each and every profile link.
And then we will also use Parsel. So if
you don't already have Parsel installed,
it's a library, really, for extracting data
points from the site similar to the Scrapy one
that we used previously.
So if you don't already have it,
you can install it by simply entering
pip install parsel. That's it, really.
So let's go here and import it. So
from parsel, we will use Selector.
Selenium also has the selector, but it's not
really that well done as something like Parsel is.
So we can copy this, and paste
this into our Terminal, hit Enter.
And then, let's see. So we can
type in here the sel = Selector
And then in open and closed
parentheses, we are going to type in
(text=driver.page_source)
So if we copy and paste this,
and go back to the Terminal,
paste this in, hit Enter, as you can see,
this will pretty much load our source code for this
specific page. So it's... when it comes to scraping,
we did response.body. In the Selenium,
it's going to be driver.page_source
So pretty simple. Let's see, sublime text,
and so let's copy and paste this.
We don't actually have to... let's
go back and enter some profile.
And let's now enter or copy and
paste this. Copy and then paste this in.
And then, finally, we can start to scrape or locate first
the data points. The first one is going to be Name.
Most of the time, it's going
to be either in h1 or h2 tags.
So let's see which one it is here, Inspect.
And here we can, pretty much,
I can see at least three different ways
to scrape this. You can scrape it by class,
and then this value by tag name of h1.
The ID can be equal to the name,
and also the class can be
equal to the, as you can see, fn,
which probably stands for full name, or something
like that. We can just scrape it by a tag name of h1
because it's probably the easiest one. Let's see.
Let's go back to the Terminal and type in,
since we are using the Parsel
Selector, we can type in sel.xpath,
and then locate every h1 tag. Hit Enter,
and Perfect. So here we can see our data.
And the syntax, it's going to be,
really, the same as with Scrapy, previously.
So we can type in text, open and closed
parentheses, and then extract_first()
So really, really simple. Hit
Enter, and, as you can see,
it's in the unicode Paul Garner, which
corresponds to this name. We can copy this,
and paste this into our text editor.
Let's name this name,
and let's see what else is going to be interesting.
Let's see... let's see, job title, for example.
So this guy is a freelance Python developer
at Depop. So we go in Inspect here on this element,
and we have the headline title. Let's see,
let's actually go back to a few more.
And let's see if it's going to be the same
data points. So the titles, for some reason,
it seems like we are not currently on
the... like we haven't logged in. This is weird.
Anyway, let's go and here see the h1 tag.
Okay, here the guy has the name,
and also, let's see, so headline title. So it seems
like it corresponds to each and every profile.
So we can copy this. And let's see if
it's also...  this is going to be the same.
So Inspect, headline title. So it
seems like it's going to be the same,
but let's actually login first and see if
the data points are going to be there.
Okay, so I'm logged in. So let's go to the
first profile, and let's see if it changed.
So it's going to be changed. So, as you can see,
scraping LinkedIn is going to be extra hard,
because the pages do differ from the time
that you are logged in and logged out.
So that's also one thing to note.
So, let's see, the name is probably not going
to be changed. So, let's see, it's going to be h1 tag
with the specific class, but scraping it
from h1 tag is going to be probably easier.
So, currently, Selenium... so if we go to the Terminal,
and type in driver.current_url, it's going to be
displaying the Google... the URL, as you can see here.
So these two pages are not loaded.
So the way that you can load them is...
let's copy this, and paste this in.
And, right now, if we go back to our Terminal,
and type in driver.current_url,
and hit Enter, as you can see,
it's going to be corresponding to this URL.
So that's also one thing to note
when it comes to scraping data with Scrapy.
Let's verify that everything is working.
To do that we go back to our text editor.
We can copy and paste this statement,
and paste this in here. But before that, sorry,
we need to also make sure that we have
our Parsel Selector at the current
page source because, previously,
it was on Google or the profile
that was logged off. Sorry.
Let's go to the text editor, and let's copy this,
paste this in, hit Enter, and perfect. So it works.
So the next one data point that we would like
to scrape is going to be job title, which
is going to be, in this case, this value.
So we go to Inspect, and let's see. So it
seems like it's going to be in the h2 tag.
So let's see if just typing
sel.xpath, select every h2 tag,
let's see, let's extract text from it and extract.
Let's see. Senior software developer at Kalo (contract)
So it seems like if we just type in extract_first()
it will locate our data. The other way that
you can scrape this data point is just by,
pretty much, copying and pasting this class.
Let's see if this is going to be working.
Let's go back to our Terminal,
and then type in sel.xpath
and then locate every class with the
previously copied class value,
and extracting text from it. Let's
see if this is going to be working,
data Senior software developer, as you
can see. So it's going to be working also here.
But let's just copy and paste this h2 tag.
So we are just going to be extracting
the first instance of the h2 tag
and extract, of course, text from it.
Let's paste this in here and name this,
for example, job_title is equal to this value.
The very next data point that we will
scrape is going to be the school.
So the school, in this case, is going to be
this data point that I'm highlighting right now.
So let's go and Inspect it. And, as you can see,
they kind of share the same classes,
which goes to pv-top-card-section, and then headline,
for example, experience, company, and also schools.
So it's going to be pretty straightforward
to scrape these data points.
However, this part of the class
will probably not be changed.
But here, this part will... may be
changed, and maybe it's dynamic.
So, as you can see, it's going
to contain the typeface or font values.
As you can see here, 17 pixel, black, 70%
This is probably something like capacity,
or something like that. So we just
need to, pretty much, scrape this class.
So let's copy and paste this in here, and perfect.
So it seems like there will be only one instance,
as you can see here. So we can
type in, in our Terminal, sel.xpath,
then in open and closed parentheses, we
type in to find every selector that starts with,
and, let's see, in the ordinary
parentheses we type in class,
and then comma, and then the value,
which is going to be, sorry, this one.
So let's see if this is going to be working.
Let's see, something is not entered correctly.
It starts... oh, sorry... with.
And let's see why this doesn't work.
So XPath error: Unregistered function in...
Let's see, this should be working.
Let's see if there is... okay, so this is
ordinary parentheses, square brackets.
Yeah, it's going to be there, and it should
be working, but starts... oh, sorry.
The "s" is missing here. Perfect.
So the "s" was... so it should be
starts with, not start with. Let's see, let's
use the text from it and use extract_first()
because there's only one element that we
are interested in. And here, as you can see,
it's going to be this value. Perfect. So, as you
can see here, we have the white space and \n,
which stands for new space, really.
And so if we copy this or new line,
let's see where we need to enter this
in our text editor. We can type in here,
for example, school is equal to this.
And then if school, so if school:
Then we will use school = school.strip()
So if we copy this statement, copy. And, let's see,
let's go back to the Terminal, paste this in, hit Enter.
And then also call in school.strip()
You will see if we paste this in,
that after we enter it here, we will not
get the new lines and white spaces.
As you can see it from here,
it's going to be changed. So if we...
so since we are going to enter
this into the CSV file, you will get,
pretty much, unordered cells. So it's probably
easier to just call a strip on it to make it more tidier.
And that will be it for this video.
In the very next one, we will continue
to scrape location, and also LinkedIn URL.
And, finally, save these data points
to the CSV file, which is going
to be named in the parameters.py file.
So I'll see you there.