Hey there! So in this section of the video,
we will write a more advanced spider.
So we will re-use our previous code that we wrote
from the previous section.
And the new spider will iterate over the container
or quote containers and iterate over pages.
So there are currently ten or so different quotes
per page and around ten or so pages.
So hopefully we will, at the end of this spider
or this section we will have around
100 or so different quotes scraped.
From each and every quote we will scrape the text from it
the author and finally the tags.
So let's begin right away.
So if we go to the Terminal
and go to our, let's maximize this.
Go and copy and paste the URL.
So type in scrapy shell and then in single
or double quotes paste the URL.
We get...
Response status 200 which is successful
and we can pretty much start to write our selectors.
So we can remove the selectors previously that we wrote,
which is h1_tag and tags.
So we can comment this out for a moment,
so it doesn't interfere.
And let's begin straight away.
So the first thing that I would do in this type of case
is isolate quote containers.
Quote container is going to represent pretty much,
this will be first container, this will be the second one.
And this will for example, third one, et cetera.
So there are currently on the home page,
ten different quotes containers.
So to do that, like anything with the scraping of the data,
you should right-click, go to the Inspect,
and then as you can see pretty much
each and every &lt;div&gt; with the class of the value,
quote, is the container.
So as you can see, so here we have our ten containers,
so we will iterate over them.
Now how do we iterate over them?
Well we'll just use a simple for loop in our spider code.
And the XPath selection to get to the
first container is pretty simple.
So what we need to do is pretty much write the selector
or the similar selector that we wrote previously,
so we type in response.xpath, and then in parentheses,
and in either single or double quotes we will find
every class instance that has the value of the quote
as you can see.
So if we just type this in we will get
ten different selectors as you can see.
So this pretty much, selector corresponds to this one.
So the first container or in the site,
this pretty much HTML node.
So we are going to assign quotes.
To be equal to our previous statement.
Let's copy this to our code right away.
So copy and then paste it into your Text Editor.
So quotes, and we will iterate it pretty much for quote,
in quotes and then we will pass this for now.
Going back to our Terminal,
we will type in, let's type in quote
And the first quote is going to be
quotes or from the quotes
and the first instance will be of course zero.
So quote is going to be pretty much this first container
from the site and if we're call in
quote.extract() and hit enter
you will see that this HTML
corresponds pretty much to this one.
So this is in the tree structure so more readable
but that's pretty much the same really
value really or the content of the page.
So that's going to be pretty much it for this video
in the very next one we will finally write
our three selectors so we will select the text, the author
and finally the tags.
So see you there.