Hey there! So in this video we will cover
logging in to the site with Scrapy, and we will do this
with the already existing code that we have
from our previous video.
So let's just double verify that everything is going
to work correctly and without any errors.
Everything is working fine, so pretty much this site
from the home page has the Login button.
After that, we will go to the /login page,
and we can type in pretty much any username and password
combo and type in Login, and we will get redirected
to the home page and here we have the Logout button,
so that pretty much means
that we are logged in successfully.
Obviously, this is just a demo site and on the real site
after you login you would get some data points, URLs,
or stuff like that which you don't normally have
without logging in, so that's the entire point
of actually using logging in.
So let's get back to the Firefox, the good old Firefox,
and let's go actually just first on the Login.
And now we can go to the Firebug.
We can go the Net Developer Tools.
As you can see from the pop-up it allows us to analyze
the network traffic or URLs
that server is going to request.
Now there are two requests,
The first one or in this case there are two of them.
The first one is going to be the POST,
and the second one is going to be the GET.
So let's just click the Login, and here,
as you can see probably, by now we have the POST and GET.
POST is going to be the most interesting one,
and here we have the statuses.
And this one is 302 which pretty much means
that we are redirected and from logging in page,
so this one we got redirected
once we are logged in to the home page.
So this pretty much means that the other URL is this one
after the redirection, so to speak,
we are going to get the home page.
We don't care too much about this page.
We just care about the POST request.
Let's actually just maximize it a little bit.
And after popping this up, we will see
that there are more than a few Tabs.
Mainly we are going to be interested in the Post one,
so here we have the three arguments.
The first one is the csrf_token.
So this is going to be a dynamically changed token,
and this is going to be definitely important for us
because without it we are not going to successfully
login to the site.
And finally we can pretty much get this password
and username combo is hard coded into our code.
They don't really matter, they can be not changed
and they are not dynamically assigned
such as this string or a token.
Let's go back to our code.
So from our code what needs to be updated
is first the imports.
So the import that we are going to use is sub module
in Scrapy called FormRequest.
So we can import that by typing in
from scrapy.http import FormRequest,
let's see, and we will use it in a moment.
So the starting URL will be not this one.
We also don't need the allowed_domains.
It's really going to make stuff complicated
without any positive sides.
The home page will not be the starting URL.
It's going to be this one, so it's going to,
let's actually go back.
The starting URL is going to be this one.
Let's see, so let's actually just rename this
to something like scrape_home_page,
and then the function, the default one,
is going to be of course parse
and it's just going to read from the all response
of course is going to be read from this page.
And finally, we are going to yield FormRequest
or return it, but before that, we will need to scrape
the csrf_token.
This is located here in the Login page so let's Inspect it
with Google, and here we have it in the &lt;input&gt; node.
Because the page is just really a demo, we can pretty much
identify exactly right away what exactly is the value
that we are looking for and, in this case,
it's going to be this string.
If we reload this page, it's just going to be,
as you will see in a moment, it's going to be completely
something different, as you can see.
So it's dynamically changed value
because after all it's a token.
So here we have in a &lt;input&gt; really HTML node.
We have the value but we will grab it
with the name and then in the name we are going
to look for this exact string, and then from then on
we can extract the value.
So to not waste any more time, let's actually go to
scrapy shell and let's test out
if we can scrape data from there.
So response.xpath and let's see we are going
to get or grab the name once again which is from the input.
But we don't care so we are going to scrape the name
with the value of csrf_token,
and here we found Selector.
So let's actually just get the HTML node
so it's in the form of a list.
So that's fine, and here we get the &lt;input&gt;
HTML part and the value which is the thing that we need.
So pretty much we need this type of data,
and to extract the value, we are just going
to type in /@value.
And this is in the form of a list so to get the unicode
we are going to just type in extract_first().
So let's copy it, let's go back to our code,
and let's call this variable name token.
Let's prettify this a little bit so it's a bit more readable
and finally I think we can pretty much return FormRequest.
Now this will read from the Login page so we will use
from_response, so to do that
we will use syntax this.
And let's see, so the first parameter here
is going to be the URL.
We can just read from the response and then we are
going to form data,
let's see, formdata.
So formdata is just going to be a dictionary,
and in that dictionary is just going
to be three dictionary items.
The first one is going to be this pretty much,
and the last two are going to be password and username.
Let's define first the dictionary keys.
So the first one is going to be this one,
so formdata is going to be this one.
And this one or the first one is obviously going to read
from the token, so it's going to be
once again dynamically changed.
The second one it's going to be password.
It doesn't matter if you put password first then,
for example, csrf or really token.
The last it's not ordered and the last one is the username.
We can hard code it and just put really anything here.
It doesn't matter as you will see in a moment.
And let's see, and we need to get callback.
So to do that or call the callback function,
so to do that type in callback is going to equal
to the self.scrape_home_page.
So it's going to go to this page and then scrape data.
Let's see if I'm missing something.
I don't think I am, but let's verify it.
It seems like everything is in the right order,
so let's go back to our Spider code and let's run it.
And it seems like it's working.
So to make sure that this is actually working,
what we need to do is call another import.
And this import is also some module in Scrapy module,
and it's called open_in_browser, so let's import it.
So from scrapy.utils.response import
open_in_browser.
And then we can just go into the function
called scape_home_page and just
open_in_browser(response).
Click Save and this is mostly used when debugging.
So if you don't know what type of page
is getting loaded, you can then just open
in Browser from the function.
For example, come and see what exactly or what data points
are available because sometimes as more and more sites
are JavaScript heavy, sometimes data points are read
from some URL or something like that from the server side.
Let's see, let's actually run it and this will actually
open the, hopefully, tmp file, as you will see in a moment.
So this is the URL
or read from the response, right,
so let's actually just run it
and you will see in a moment, perfect.
So it's opened and here from the home page we get the Logout
button which pretty much means that we are logged in.
So if we go to the home page, as you can see,
this the, once again from the Internet,
so we are not logged in here and from the tmp
or temporary file, we are logged in.
So that pretty much means that we are good to go
and that our logging in worked perfectly well.
Again, this is just for demo purposes.
You would log into real sites with pretty much similar
or exactly like this.
Most of the time the site will have some kind of token
and that password and username, of course,
you will define it as you register and that would
pretty much be it for this video.
In the very next one we will talk more about how you can
run Scrapy spider without needing to define the entire
project tree as we did here, so you can bottom line run it
with python foo.py.
So see you in the very next video!