Hey there!
So we are continuing from our last video
where I showed or introduced Selenium with Scrapy
or using Selenium with Scrapy.
So let's continue.
The first thing that we are going to do is navigate
or figure out what exactly this HTML node is
and how to actually extract it
and then finally click it with Selenium.
So let's try to do that.
We will go to the Inspect,
and then see that this next button
is in the first and foremost list
that has the class next in it,
and then finally it goes to the &lt;a&gt; tag,
and that &lt;a&gt; tag has the href and then the text in it.
So we are going to pretty much write the XPath
in the Selenium that goes to every &lt;a&gt; tag
and then only extract or get the selectors
that are going to have the "next" string in it.
To do that we are going to just type in driver
and then find element.
Here we have to find element by class name,
css selector, id and stuff like that.
For now let's just use the XPath, the good old XPath,
and then the syntax for the XPath is really the same
as it is in the Scrapy.
So we will collect every &lt;a&gt; tag that has the text "next".
Let's see if this is found, perfect,
and let's see if we can click it in the Selenium.
Here's pretty much the syntax
how to click on the element
and this should load the seventh page.
So let's see if this will work.
Let's see if it works.
Perfect.
So let's try it once again.
It should go to the eighth page.
And it goes to the eighth page which is perfect.
So let's copy and paste this to our Spider code,
and first let's define while loop
and we will try and use try and except logic.
For now we will pass it.
And let's define next page button
as just the next_page variable.
And finally we will have to use sleep function
which is going to inherit from Python built-in library
called time, and we will manually sleep for three seconds,
to not get any type of errors or stuff like that
where we are loading still next page
and then the script will try to click it once again
because Selenium is extremely slow compared to Scrapy.
So we will just use the sleep function.
And you have in Selenium, for example,
call to pretty much wait for some presence
of the HTML node, for example,
when the first image of the book
or, for example, the better choice
would be the last image of the book is present,
then the scraper could continue.
That could take something like a second or a millisecond,
it really depends on the site,
but that's definitely a better choice than using this.
But as this is just an example,
this is just going to be more than enough.
And let's call the log message.
To do that we will just type in this
and just type in Sleeping for 3 seconds.
And let's see what else needs to be done.
We need to click it of course.
So next_page, we are going to click this.
And finally we will pretty much reuse this part of the code,
since in a second here we are going to be
or scrape the first page of the books
and parse the first 20 book URLs
to the function called parse_book.
And then in this loop we are going to pretty much iterate
over 49 of remaining pages.
And here we are going to try every time
to click the next_page button and add an exception.
So we will add the exception
that is going to be called NoSuchElementException,
and this will actually go
to the from selenium.common.exceptions
import NoSuchElementException.
So let's actually see if this is importing it rightly.
Perfect, it works.
So I've spelt everything right.
And we will not use pass, we will use the break command.
But before that this code will be only executed once again
once we are on the last page,
and that is because the next page will not be present
in our last page.
So we will first call out our log message
which will print out,
let's see, for example, No more pages to load.
And then we will finally exit our driver instance.
To do that we just type in,
driver.quit()
and then we will break from our while loop here.
And let's see what else here we need.
I've also seen that for some reason on this site
the catalogue has to be added
in this type of URL I am not even sure why.
But let's actually try to do it without it,
and I think we will actually get the 404 pages.
So let's see.
Let's see, something is not working,
so driver is not defined.
That is because I've used driver here
without the self in it.
So let's try it once again.
And, as you can see, 404 pages are reported,
and that is because the /catalogue,
and this specific part of the URL
has to be integrated.
So we will just use the, let's see.
We have the catalogue here.
So I'll just copy and paste it and add it.
Let's actually just do something like this.
Let's see if this will work.
It has to contain, the last character has to be slash.
Let's run it once again and see if it works.
Let's see, it's first the log messages
that it's getting reported.
It seems like it's working correctly.
As you can see, our sleeping for 3 seconds
is getting reported,
200 is the response status, so it seems like it's working.
So let's see on the Selenium side if it's working correctly.
It's iterating other pages, as you can see,
we are currently on the seventh page.
Requests are getting generated.
And finally we can close this out
because it means that it will work,
and then you can yield title or price
or something third as a data point.
Yeah, that would be pretty much it for this video.
In the very next one we will actually iterate over pages,
so do the same exactly thing with the Scrapy,
not with Selenium, and you will see the speed difference.
That it's quite large between the two tools.
Using Scrapy is definitely way to go in this type of scrape.
And we will actually go and scrape
some interesting data points, such as title, image URL,
price, description and all of these different data fields
that are present in all of the book URLs.
Talk soon!