Hi there!
So today we are going to learn more about Scrapy arguments,
what they are and how you can use them in your
code.
In this specific example we will use it
to isolate different categories.
So for example if you want to scrape just Philosophy related books.
In this case we will gather
11 books and will only scrape pretty much this URLs.
And then from then on extract data points
from the code that we built last time which
we are going to reuse.
So the code that needs to be updated is pretty short.
We need to remove the start_urls and then
define our constructor which of course is going to be
"__init__"
And then define two arguments, the first one is going to
be obviously "self" and then the second one
will be "category".
This can be pretty much anything
but in this case let's use just category.
And then we type in
"self.start_urls = [category]",
which will correlate or which will be
this URL for example.
So let's save the code, go back to the root directory,
open Terminal and then type in "scrapy crawl books".
So this obviously stays the same.
And then we need to append "-a"
which stands for arguments obviously.
And then define the category, which correlates to
this argument in our constructor and we type in here
single or double quotes
in this case and then copy and paste this URL, and here the item_scraped_count should be 11,
which it is which is perfect.
So let's try one another different category.
Let's say for example we want to scrape History related books here.
We should get 18 results.
Or 18 books scraped.
So let's see.
"-a"
And then the "category" which is going to be the URL, perfect.
So that'll be it for this video.
Once again the arguments or Scrapy arguments
can be used for isolating different categories.
For example if you have thousands and thousands of
History related books or if you need to in future
for example run it for Science books only or stuff like that
or you need to assign some special rule
or something like that for your scraper then you should
use Scrapy arguments and that would it for this video.
In the very next one, we will talk about
a Scrapy function called close. Talk soon!