Hey there! So today we are going to learn
how to install Scrapy on a Windows machine.
So if we head over to the scrapy.org,
then go to the "Documentation",
it will redirect us to the latest documents.
Then we should head over to the "installation guide".
After that we can either install Anaconda or Miniconda.
The tool that we'll install is called Anaconda.
So then we go to "download Anaconda"
and this will open a new tab to specify
the operating system that you have,
so since this is the installation process for Windows
we will go over to Windows,
and then here we have four different packages.
We'll install Python 2.7 64-bit installer.
Click here to download it, save the file and click here "x",
and then wait [some time] to be downloaded.
After that, we open the file,
and once this prompts usو we will click here "Run".
The installation process is fairly simple
and straightforward, "Next", "I Agree",
and check here "All Users".
Click here "Yes", "Next", and then
"Add Anaconda to the system PATH environment variable"
and click here "Install".
Installation will take a few minutes,
maybe up to 10 minutes or so,
so I'll pause the video right now
and then get back to you as soon as it's done.
Okay, so it's completed, we click here "Next",
and then we uncheck these two options,
and finally click "Finish".
We head over to the documentation
and then pretty much just copy and paste this command.
We go and hit the Windows key, then type in "cmd"
which is going to be "Command Prompt",
and then just paste the command
"pip install scrapy" and hit Enter.
This will install Scrapy
and all the dependencies that Scrapy relies on,
and it should be completed in 30 or so seconds.
Some of the dependencies are already, as you can see,
all requirements are already satisfied,
so the installation should not take more
than 10 seconds right now.
And if you encounter any type of issues or errors,
make sure to head over to our Q&amp;A section,
and just really ask questions
or really ask about the error that you received.
So as you can see, it's completed.
If we type in right now "python"
and then type in "import scrapy" to verify
that everything is installed correctly,
we should not get any types of errors,
so as you can see it works perfectly well.
So that will be it for this video
and I'll see you in the very next one.