Hey there! So this is our second part of the
video. And in this part with the eplanning spider,
we will pretty much go . . . after
we go to this type of pages,
which was done or handled in the
previous or first part of this section,
we will then go to the Received
Applications listings. So let's do that.
So to do that we, of course, as always, need
to inspect first how exactly we will get to
the similar to this URL. So, let's see,
here we have the div and also span, and
finally the href in the "a" tag. So it
seems like we can find every "a" tag that
has this text, or we can select this class,
and then use following or following-sibling;
following-sibling will be
probably the better idea.
And then after we get our following-sibling, we can then
select first instance of the "a" tag and select href.
So enough talk. Let's go to our Terminal.
Let's copy this link and paste it in. First,
we'll fetch it. So fetch and then this URL.
Okay, so let's see. So we are
looking to get the class with this value.
So we can copy this, go back to the
Terminal, and then type in our XPath selector.
So response.xpath, then we will find
all class or classes that have this value.
Hit Enter. And as you can see here,
we got one instance, which is great.
And after that, we can type in either
following and then extract . . . well,
this will extract probably more than one
instance, as you will see. As you can see,
there are a lot of the different hrefs,
so we don't need this. So there's two
ways that you can get to the first href,
which is going to be this one. So we are
looking to get this one. You can use
extract_first() which will select it,
and you can also use here list slicing in
the "a" tag. So if you type this, you can see
that it's going to be received or
SearchListing/RECEIVED URL.
And then the third thing that you can use
is remove this and use following-sibling.
And then, yeah, we don't need here list slicing
because this will select just the first
instance, as you can see. So then we
need to go into href. So since we are
currently here, so we then need to
go to the href. And, finally, by calling in,
of course, the extract_first() at the
end, we are going to get to our URL.
Here as you can see, this is the part of the
URL, so we will have to use response.urljoin,
and then paste or, really, name the variable
name, and then paste it into the parenthesis.
So let's go to the text editor, and let's name this
app_url is equal to the statement that we
previously wrote. And then we just need
to yield the request, so yield Request,
response.urljoin, and then in it we
can copy and paste this app_url.
And then define our callback,
which is going to be equal parse_form. In this function,
we will pretty much . . . let's actually type it first.
In this function, as I was saying,
we will play around with the form request
from the response, as you will
see. So it's going to be pretty interesting,
as you will see in the very
next video. So (self,  response):
And for now, we will pass it.
Just to verify that everything is
working fine on this front. So we
can save it, go back to the Terminal,
and then call in our scrapy crawl
command. Hit enter, and let's see.
So 200 redirection pages, and only
one 404 page which is, of course,
previously mentioned, robot.txt
page. And let's see, the URLs,
everything is working fine. So I'll
then see you in the very next video.