Hey there! So today we will build a completely
new Spider, which will crawl the entire site
and scrape a URL from each page that is found.
The site is this one, so,
books.toscrape.com. And let's create our
Scrapy spider finally.
So let's navigate to the Desktop.
And let's create it. So
to do that we can type in scrapy
startproject, and the name of the
project can be books_crawler.
Let's navigate here to the root directory.
It seems like everything is set correctly.
Let's type in now scrapy genspider,
which will generate Spider. And let's call
this Spider books. And then allowed_domains
is going to be this URL.
Let's go straight to the Spider code,
which is located in the Spiders folder.
What needs to be changed here is
we should remove the www.
The reason why is because if we don't
do that we will encounter some errors.
So let me actually show it to you
in a moment so we can test it at least perfectly,
fine the Scrapy Shell.
So loading this page will work.
And response.status that is as you can see is 200.
But if we add the www. part in the URL,
as you will see there is twisted.internet.error.
So that will definitely cause issues.
Let see, I haven't exited correctly
the Terminal, um so just make sure that www.
once again part is not present
in the start_urls, and that allowed_domains
is the correct URL.
And let's see what else we can do.
So pretty much the first thing that we
need to do is remove the Spider,
or the import for the Spider.
We will not use the default Spider,
we will use CrawlSpider.
Now CrawlSpider is going to to have some
other attributes and reserved names
and stuff like that, just like the
Spider had it. And the one of them will
be the Rules, as you will see in a moment.
But let's first import it, so from
scrapy.spiders import CrawlSpider.
And we will also grab the Rule sub module.
Just like with the Spider, so pretty much
the Spider as I'm referring to Spider,
I mean Spider from the previous videos,
that we used CrawlSpider that has alongside
with the name, allowed_domains,
start_urls, reserved words, also it has the
rules variable. Now rules variable is going
to set one or more Rule really.
Simple as that. And in the first Rule
and only Rule that we will collect or get
is going to have object called LinkExtractor().
This object is pretty much going to
tell us that once we are in
some specific page we would like to grab
all of the URLs, no matter how many of them
there are, and then we can select some other
attributes and parse different type
of pages and stuff like that.
So let's collect or get the two other
arguments that we will use. So the first one
is going to be callback. Now previously
we talked or called, better said,
callback would be self.parse.
So this would work but by syntax
in Python at least, since this is variable name,
this will not work, so it has to have
the single or double quotes surrounding it
and also self, we don't need it,
because it's in the same sort of
layer so to speak.
And finally the other thing is that
the parse function name is
reserved just for the Spider.
The default Spider that Scrapy uses
so we can use any other function
variable names such as, parse_page.
The last attribute that we will use
is called follow. Follow is going to be
either True or False, so boolean expression.
And if set to True, it will once it goes to
the start_urls, or once it scrapes this page,
LinkExtractor() will collect all of the URLs
present in this page. And if follow is
set to True, it will for example collect
this URL and then this URL it will collect
the books URL and go to the next page,
collect all of the categories if it's
not yet scraped, and go to the next page
and stuff like that by default,
if I haven't mentioned already,
Scrapy will filter out, duplicate Requests.
So if this type of pages or category related pages
are scraped once, they will not be scraped twice.
So let's see if set to False, as you
will see in a moment, the Spider
is just going to go to the homepage,
process the links and pretty much stop
and not work, so, let's actually save it.
So let's see if everything is in the
correct order, so I haven't added LinkExtractor,
LinkExtractor is
from scrapy.linkextractors import LinkExtractor.
Save it and let's actually run this.
So let's see if it works.
And it seems like I haven't done something
correctly so lets see what is the issue.
So it's invalid syntax, and it seems like
this should work, so let's see. Perfect.
So 75 as you can see, responses, are generated,
or better said 74, with the 200 response status,
and 1 is for the 404s. So let's see,
I think that is the robots.txt? Perfect.
So it seems like Scrapy in this type of,
or this version at least, is going to
first page that is going to, that it's
going to go to, is going to be
robots.txt type of page,
and since this type or site doesn't have them,
so let's copy and paste it, to verify it,
as you can see 404, so it's not found,
so this site doesn't have the, or doesn't
contain the 404 pages, or sorry robots type of pages,
this will not be of course processed.
So let's see what else we can do with this.
Let's see, from Terminal, let's try to run it
once again and see. 74 only pages are successful.
Perfect. So there are not any errors,
which is perfect also. And now let's talk
about the LinkExtractor arguments.
One of them is deny_domains. And let's
type in, in the parentheses, domain name,
such as google.com. If we save this, and
then just scrape it as it is, you will see
that there isn't really anything changed.
This is because the books.toscrape.com
will not contain any Google-related
pages, or better said, domain names,
such as google.com. But this is an especially
good idea if you know that the site actually has
this type of related pages, because
then you will get potentially banned or
thrown CAPTCHA with Google. And the
spider will actually take longer to complete.
Also, some of the pages or domains
that you would like to avoid will be,
for example, social media accounts
such as Facebook, Instagram,
Google+, Twitter, LinkedIn, etc.
because they are really restrictive
when it comes to scraping. And spider,
once again, or better said, a crawler will be faster
without scraping the necessary,
or unnecessary, pages.
Another argument that
LinkExtractor provides is called allow.
So this one, for example, let's say we have a
task to only scrape the music-related pages.
So we will just type in here music,
and then save it. So this will process
the pages that have the music in the URL,
such as this one. So it will actually go
to the music-related category, and then
scrape only the URLs that have music in them.
So, for example, this page will be
scraped. And if we run it, you will see
that it's going to be extremely fast because
there isn't a lot of pages to be processed.
And, as you can see, it's already
finished. We already got some
filtered out results from the category.
And, yeah, that will be pretty much it
for this video. So, as you can see, in around
16 or so lines we built the entire crawler
that you can use to, pretty much,
index the entire domain.
So if we want to index
every URL from some domain,
you will type in yield URL, and then just
response.url. Some of the... another use case
for this simple scraper or crawler
can be for extracting email addresses
from entire domains. So you can fetch all of
the different emails or scrape forums, etc.
Thanks for watching.