So today we are going to learn how to scrape tables from the site the site that we are going to be using
is this one.
And this is sort of universal way or path with tips and tricks on how to successfully or more efficiently
and easy scrape or parse the table data or table rows and then really the table data itself, or a.k. the values.
So let's begin!
So we go to the inspection tool to figure out how Firstly this table on the site is.
really presented on this page.
So here is the iframe as you can see HTML and all and most of the time really will encounter table
notes and then in those table notes you will encounter table rows in the first table row.
Most of the time of course will be the table header and then in that table header we will get the table
data points.
So this will be the first table data, and this will be the second table data.
The third one and fourth one, etc.
So this side uses the divs and classes.
Why?
Because probably because it's really loaded in a matter of request and that request will be in the source.
So if we try to parse this table from here from this specific yourself with Scrapy it will last forever
because it's going to be long.
So it's actually trying to do it to compete and go to the Terminal and then type in the shell and let's
open it right away or see how exactly Scrapy sees it so we taken your response and it is going to be
loaded right away for fear of if it's going to be over.
Of course you just need to.
Let's use the most easier solution.
So I was thinking about writing some selector to select maybe just the team names or something like that.
But you can go more easier by just typing in response.body, hit Enter, and then go to the site.
Let's see for example copy and paste "Golden State".
And then Find in your prompt and it's going to be located I'll see "Houston Rockets vs.
Golden State".
So this is not what we are looking for.
And so trying to click once again fine you will see that they will not be caught.
So this is the most easier way to figure out know the data is going to be in the Scrapy response.
If it's not then there are some specific route to the server that Scrapy will not see it really.
And that is why that's great.
OK so let's copy and paste this URL to the table itself and open it.
And you'll see the.
It's going to be loaded without the rest of the page.
So you can go to the Terminal and then "fetch" this specific URL, hit Enter, and then once again type in response.body
hit Enter and then navigate to "Golden State", you can see here
that is going to be loaded in the -as you can see here- class with the value "team" which is perfect so everything is fine.
So once again as previously discussed try to show you sort of a universal way of how to parse
the tables if you can for stripping tables and you don't know exactly.
You always have our assistance in the Q&A section so make sure you get over there and ask any questions
or really any concerns that you have.
And I'll try to get back to you as soon as possible.
So the idea once again is to make this as efficient as possible to do that when you encounter scripting
or famous themselves.
Always try to isolate us the main why we would like to do that is to further isolate the table data
or generally data points that we like straight.
So whenever we have maybe some conflict sites such for example go to the page on the first page.
So for example this one.
So if you maybe like to just grab the first let's say first call from the tables and then if you parse
this page as it is and it works then it also selects this or really this year table data themselves.
And of course you wouldn't really want to do that.
So the idea here that I'm trying to get at is that whenever you encounter more complex or really larger
sites or pages than sell make sure to isolate the page as much as possible really to make it more efficient
and cleaner also.
So I thought let's go to inspect and see how exactly we can get our table rose isolated.
So we have here in class with the sites and then in it.
But there is as you can see is iterating over them.
They will select each row which is a good thing.
And then we have the class and here the first one side side-over, side-fav, and then the second one side side-under.
...
So it seems like the only thing that is going to be changed to year for the first one and then every
other one is going to be this year over again either.
So we have a solution for that.
All right sort of more complex selector or selector that will fetch two values as a walk.
So let me show you how to do that.
You can go to our text editor to make it more cleaner since here we have Python syntax highlighting and
let's copy and paste this into our Terminal.
Of course the selector itself is going to be fairly straightforward.
So you're right we talk about at first and then we select every class and then we can pretty much just copy and paste this value
and if we copy this and then paste it into our Terminal, hit Enter, you will see only one selector, which is good indeed.
Then we if navigate back to the text editor, really the syntax it's going to be just one character
or writing two or really few or doesn't really expand in this case, the selector and is going to be this
character.
So if we copy and paste this here this will work.
So let me show you how or why it's going to be working.
It's going to be working because we just put this sort of separator from the first one and then the
second selector as teacher.
So it's all going to be selected in the first instance watching and.
We would like to also grab the other eight points or select first in this case to see where exactly
when you go into your.
And so it's going every other day lunch so if we copy and paste it here we can see it tonight and so
on and all should and then 30 instances we did everything right.
OK so we need to go and paste this new value to the row itself so you can use navigate back to the terminal
and paste it in here.
We should get a bunch of different selectors.
So everything should be working.
And let's call this verbal main roles.
And then just to verify that everything's working.
Should get in the blanks.
We should get the mail you turned perfect.
So also this works.
So this again is just my way of thinking or really my workflow.
Then the next step in my thinking is to further isolate neuros just like you for example roll and then
you go to your office.
And then just selecting the first instance or not right index.
And then we call in Roths cracked open close branches and then pretty much we will write to our selectors
from this role.
So here we get the output or really ational lot south and you can see the class goals that.
So if you like to extract the names or the first Calo from the table we need to type in row not that
we want to use respons that's bad because we are in our custom written or developed really selector
switch here.
If we open this and close the parentheses then typing in the Singler about votes.
If we died or if we exclude the dot and just typing to select every class we see with the team as in
I will select everything.
So what would like to do is just select the first one.
So I believe this was previously discussed but just make sure that it's recent is on the same page.
You need to also include that always when writing from the Custom Slipper's type.
Now we do that.
You can see the Golden State will be selected.
And of course to select the text itself.
You just need to type in text and then extracts and you get your data.
So for selecting every other data point here you can write just another sample.
First we go to the inspect and then see your class with the line book so you go quizzes and then let's
go first to the Sublime Text and then type in course response.xpath or sorry row.xpath
again always include a dot and then we need to select every class with the "line book" in it.
And you can call this and then go to the Terminal and paste it in here.
Time for an S Let's see what else we need.
So we need to further isolate this so we need to go into learning books then.
And then finally the value itself which is going to be located in spec so this should be fairly straightforward.
Let's see if you go to atec and then strapper you Tanter and see here our data.
It seems like the last one is not going to be in slogans.
So I see that is the case of it so it seems like the last value as you can see is going to be
-240
However for me which is what you did here but the last value is going to be included.
So what we need to do here is first inspect the elements and see what's up.
And as you can see here in the "line book" we need to go into the a tag and then we get our data here.
So we can't or we really need to go into just the tags and then span as previously.
So what we need to do here is simply go into our tax shelter open this value as it is and then type
in force sort of character for writing two or more different selectors and that basically means year
and so the go to the terminal.
We actually need to compare this.
This is going to be easier to copy and paste.
Let's go to the text editor where we need to copy this.
And so this should or is going to be going into a tag and span and then text.
So if we paste it here right now another time and then exclude the a tag or sorry the span tag by deleting
span element and finally copy and paste our data...
we should be good to go and we should also select this value.
So let's see this is going to work.
So we can hear the temper and that's what we are missing here.
Of course the abstract Tanter and truancy are sort of empty value appearing.
So everything we know we're right to ask and see.
So that would be a different issue though.
Again this is just my way on when or how I approach when I encounter scrapin tales.
And once again though normally really is going to be a bit more secure than stripping other data points
from the site itself.
So once again if you encounter any kind issues or if you have any further questions make sure to head
over to our Q&amp;A section and then get back to you again as soon as I can.
Thanks for watching this video and I'll see you in the very next video.