Hey there! So in this section we will
learn how to scrape JSON specific pages.
We will use a site called Trump Twitter
Archive dot com for scraping these type of pages,
and here's how this will actually
work. So after we go to the home page,
we will see here Latest Tweets, and
then see all. So then if we click here,
we have or it redirects us to the /archive.
After that, as you can see, there will be,
so to speak, a never [ending] page
with the data. So, most of the time,
what you will then do here is go to
Inspect, then, finally, to the Network,
and then reload the page. So if we do this,
we will see a bunch of different requests.
What we are mainly interested in is going
to be, after we go to this specific tab,
is the JSON files. So whenever you
see JSON requests, most of the time
they will contain data in the JSON files. Okay?
So as you can see here from the Response tab,
after we go to it, 2009, this
corresponds, pretty much,
to all of the tweets archive in from the 2009,
all the way to the 2017. So if we copy this,
so copy link address, and then paste it in,
you will see that data is right now, sort of,
unreadable, right? So... but if we copy
this, and then open our text editor,
paste it in, and then use formatting
for JSON, you will see now
that data is in the JSON format. So it's going to be
extremely easy to scrape this type of information.
Whenever you see that JSON files are available,
then you can quickly write spider,
and don't bother, really,
with the scraping of the HTML,
and figuring out first if you
will isolate maybe rows,
or maybe just scrape all the data at once, etc.
This is 10 times easier, really. So
for now, let's go to the Desktop.
And I've created just a sample spider
with the startproject and genspider.
So after you go to the spiders, let's open this.
As you can see, it's nothing unusual.
So if we just do this... and
the starting URL will be, for example,
let's say we want to scrape just the tweets
from 2017. So we can copy this link address,
go back to the sublime text, and paste
the URL here. Now if we open the Terminal,
and open mainly the scrapy shell... okay?
So we type in scrapy shell,
and then paste the URL to the JSON file,
and then type in response.body.
And, as you can see, it's going to be our previously
opened JSON file. And if we type in view(response),
to open this, this will be opened.
As you can see, via your text editor.
That's also how we know that
this is a different type of page.
As you can see, it's going to be
or have extension dot txt.
So let's go back to the Terminal. So the
way that you parse JSON file is via or, really,
built in Python module called JSON.
So what you need to do is just use
command import json. Then we can call in
jsonresponse variable name is equal to the json.loads.
Loads is, pretty much, load
stands for loading, of course.
And then "s" will stand for string. So load
string, and we will then load response.body, really, or
pretty much all of the content
that I'm highlighting right now.
Hit Enter, and then if you type in jsonresponse, hit Enter,
you will see that it's going to be,
sort of, more readable, prettified.
So the text that I'm highlighting right now is
one tweet, and then we can quickly just
write a simple for loop, as you will see
in a moment. And just iterate over each
and every tweet, and then from each and
every tweet, we can grab, pretty much,
all of the data points that you can see here
from this note. So let's go to the text editor.
So what we need to do here
is import the JSON module,
and here in the parse function, we call in
our jsonresponse = json.loads
and then in the parentheses (response.body),
which, of course, will list out or
get us the source code or the text. And,
finally, then we can start to iterate over every tweet.
So for tweet in jsonresponse, then we can type in
or let's actually just go to the
Terminal. So we can type in
jsonresponse is equal to the, let's say,
or sorry, tweet = jsonresponse,
and then use the first instance. And
then we can type in tweet, hit Enter.
And as you can see, this is our or this will be
our first tweet. So then we can figure out
quickly what exactly data points we can
grab. We can just grab, maybe, just the
text from it or, really, any other data
point that you see here. And the way that
you grab it, it's pretty straightforward.
So we can just call in yield right away,
and then let's first define. So let's call
all of these different data points one by one.
So created_at, favorite_count, then also ID, in_reply,
is_retweet... so you just copy and paste
this... retweet_count, source, and, finally, the text.
Okay? So let's indent this properly.
Okay, perfect. So let me actually show you
how to extract from the JSON notes.
So after we type in tweets, as you can see
we have here, all of the dictionary keys
and dictionary values. So it's going to
be, pretty much, the same as we're doing it.
I mean, this is actually a dictionary,
so all we're doing here is going to grab...
if we want to grab this value,
we will type in tweet,
and then in the square brackets, we can, pretty much,
copy and paste this here, the dictionary key,
and then hit Enter. And as you can see,
here is the corresponding value to this one.
It's easy as pie, as you can see. If you
want to extract just the text from it,
then you can then type in, in the
either single or double quotes, text.
And as you can see here, we get our value
returned. So it couldn't really be simpler.
So let's go to the sublime text, and
let's right away select every instance
of our data point, and type into
it. And then in the square brackets,
we will leave this open as of right now. And
let's quickly copy this, all of the data points,
and select every instance of the
square brackets, and paste this in.
So if we save this, and then go
back to the Terminal, and run it,
so with scrapy crawl. Let's see how our spider is named.
So it's named tweets. So scrapy crawl tweets,
hit Enter, and let's see,
in the syntax, let's see what's up. Okay.
So I forgot the comma sign, of course. Okay, so if
we save this right now, go back to the Terminal,
and then hit Enter, let's see,
cannot import name Scrapy.
Let's see, from scrapy import... yeah,
silly mistake. Okay, let's run it right now.
And, as you can see, let's see, we scraped
1500 results. And it's done, as you can see,
this was done in a few seconds or, really,
second or two. That is because every tweet
is on the same page. So it's
extremely efficient, as you can see.
So if we wanted to add, maybe, let's see,
data from 2016, we can copy this link,
go back to the sublime text, and
then input it in the start URLs,
save it, go back to the Terminal,
and then rerun the spider.
And let's see how many pages
there will be scraped now.
So 5780 tweets are going to be scraped.
So if we then, let's say, use the -o items.csv
or list data into the CSV file,
let's go to the files,
go back to the root directory, and here
we have our files. So let's open it,
and let's open it once again. As you can see,
this is our data. So bottom line is that
whenever you see JSON pages are
generated, we add the Network tab.
Then you can, pretty much, rest assured
that scraping will be done more easier,
because most of the time they
will list out their data in a clear format.
Then what you need to do is use just the JSON
module and load the string or the response.body,
and then you can quickly figure out
by using simple for loop how, exactly,
you can extract data points
straight from the JSON file.