Hey there! So we are continuing from our
latest video, and the next data point
that we will scrape is going to be location.
So location is going to be found from here,
as you can see, London, United Kingdom.
So we go in and Inspect it.
And it's similar to the last one,
so pv-top-card-section__school
Here we have pv-top-card-section__location
So since we already have the code,
we can type in the... let's see, for example,
let's copy and paste this whole statement as it is,
and name it, of course, location
variable name is equal to the, this one.
And then just enter the location instead of school.
I believe this will work. Yeah, it should be working.
So, let's see. Let's copy the statement,
paste this into our Terminal, hit Enter. Perfect.
As you can see, it's going to be
locating the London, United Kingdom.
Let's see, the latest data point that
we can scrape is going to be the URL.
And if you remember correctly, it's going to be
simple as entering driver.current_url. Hit Enter.
And, as you can see, it's going
to be corresponding to this URL.
So we can copy this, and
paste this into our text editor,
call this, for example,
linkedin_url = driver.current_url
So the, let's see, next thing that we can do is,
after we run this, so after the script,
we'll load each and every URL.
In our case, it's going to be 10 URLs.
We can print our results that are scraped from here.
So to do that we will just use the print statement,
and we can... first, let's type in here the
new lines. So to do that, we type in '\n'
and then... in between it, so it's more
readable, as you will see in a moment.
So... and then we can type in first the
name, which is going to be located here.
So we can copy this, and paste this into here.
Then the second data point is going to be job_title.
So we type in 'Job Title: ' + job_title
The third data point is school,
so print 'School:  ' + school
and then location, and also LinkedIn URL,
so print 'Location: ' + location
And, finally, the URL. So we can type in just the URL.
And this is the, yeah, this is the data point.
So, finally, we will load our CSV file, which the name,
it's going to inherit from the  parameters.py file.
Let's see. Let's do this somewhere,
for example, here. So we can type in...
first, of course, we need to import. So
we import CSV as a standard module.
And then we can type in here:
writer = csv.writer
And then in open and closed parentheses, we open.
The file name is going to be the first parameter,
which is going to be from the parameters.file_name.
And then we type in our second parameters,
second, sorry, parameter, which is going to be 'wb'
This, pretty much, corresponds to writing to the file.
And then we type in first the writerow. And then the
first row, of course, is going to be our header row.
So we type in here the Name. The
second one is the... let's see.
We can, pretty much, just do this. So
we can copy this, and paste this here,
so Job Title, comma. The third one is going to be
School. The fourth one is going to be Location.
So we copy this, paste this in, and
the latest one is going to be URL.
So the syntax, really, for writing to the CSV file,
it's pretty simple, as you can see.
We, again, just load the writer, and then writerow,
and with the corresponding list of items
that we would like to add. So this will write to
the first row, which is corresponding to our header.
So we are naming it accordingly.
Then what we'll need to do...
so, currently, we are into, or in the for loop,
which is going to be iterated
over all of our collected from the Google
search query, all of our linked in URLs.
So we here type in writer, and
then also... sorry, writer.writerow
And then we type in here the name,
and then we can encode it with the utf-8,
just to make sure that it will work.
Then the second data point is... sorry.
This will be in the list because writerow, as you
saw here, is going to be in the list of the items.
So the second data point... let's actually copy this.
So, let's see, name, job_title,
so school, location, linkedin_url
If we copy this, and then paste it somewhere here,
and then we can type in here to speed it up a little bit --
this boring part. We type in also here utf-8.
We do encoding just to make sure that
all the characters are going to get loaded.
We wrap our list of items in
square brackets, and then writerow
in ordinary brackets. And to make
sure that everything is working correctly,
let's see, let's save the file,
and let's run it.
This... let's actually just test it out, also,
once again. I believe everything will be working fine.
So we're importing CSV.
Yeah, it should be working.
So let's go back to our Desktop, and
finally run our script. So open the Terminal,
change the directory to the Desktop,
and then type in python script.py,
and then hit Enter. As you can see,
results_file.csv file is auto-generated.
Right now, it's not populated yet
because we haven't scraped anything.
And we also load LinkedIn, just
to have the profiles ready to scrape.
We're entering this search query, and then
we should start to iterate over profiles,
and this is the first one. So, let's see if this
is going to be working. Okay, let's see.
It's not going to be found. So, let's see,
print 'School, as you can see here,
we don't get the school name, so then we get
the TypeError cannot, really, list out the string,
and also the NoneType objects. So
this is found, let's see, from here.
So school is going to be empty. So what I
do in this type of case is, really, write function,
which is going to be going something
like, let's name it, for example, validate_field
And then type in here (field) as a
parameter. And here we can type in if field:
then we will pass it. Because if field is
present, then it's not really needed, right?
And then we type in here else:
field is equal to empty string,
and then, finally, we return field.
So I'll explain, also, once again, this function
or what exactly it does, in a moment.
So we can copy this. And then, let's see,
we can somewhere here, do something like, let's see,
name, job_title, school, location, and
linkedin_url. Copy all of these different data points,
paste them in, indent them correctly, and
then, once again, do something like this.
And then here we can add our function,
which is going to be going into, let's see,
validate_field, if I remember correctly. Yeah.
And in the open and closed parentheses, we
can add our field. So, in this case... let's see,
in this case, on this profile, we haven't
gotten any school. So let's close this.
So we will... after it goes here,
it will validate our school field.
So if we go to the validate_field function, if field:
it will pass it. So, in this case, since field
is not defined or none, it will go to the else,
and set the field as an empty string, which
it also is, really, because there isn't, really, any field.
And then it will finally return field. If we...
let's save this. If we go to the CSV file and open it,
you will see only header. So
this is because we haven't actually
scraped or actually gotten to the
second writerow statement in our script.
So script is saved. So we can
go back to our Terminal,
and run once again our script. Let's fill this in.
So, right now, it should go to google.com
and enter our search query.
And, finally, we should go to the Paul's,
or first, really, LinkedIn profile page.
Okay, perfect. So it works. And, as you
can see here, school is going to be empty.
Location is going to be populated,
and every, really, other data point here
is going to be populated, since we
added new lines, as you can see from...
let's go back to our sublime text.
Since we added the new lines,
the Terminal, really, output is going
to be a lot more readable, as you can see.
Let's see, let's minimize this. And, let's see,
so this is the first, second, third, fourth, fifth.
So let's wait a half a minute or so after
this is all finished. So, as you can see,
this also last person didn't have the school.
This one has all of the other data points.
So everything is collected, since it's
going to be listed on the profile page.
And it should be, for a profile or two,
it should be now completed.
So let's wait until it's done.
Okay, perfect. So it's done.
If we go to the results_file.csv,
it's going to be populated with the
data fields, as you can see from here.
So this will be it for this video. In the
very next one, we will iterate, once again,
or, really, run the script, once again, and click on
the Connect button on each and every profile.
So I'll see you in the very next video.